<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My digital journey</title>
    <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My digital journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 18:50:18 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agent Ready Platform Repo</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/agent-ready-platform-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 18:50:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/agent-ready-platform-repo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi! It&amp;rsquo;s been a minute! Been trying to keep up with the latest trends in AI. Honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s almost a full-time job.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been following what the capabilities are for quite some time now. I remember when Prompt engineer was the next thing, then came context engineering. Then we had MCP servers and agents&amp;hellip; whole fleets!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agents really changed the game! The latest addition is skills. Skills seem very promising&amp;hellip; Here&amp;rsquo;s where my experiment led me&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entra Id Access Review</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/entra-id-access-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 12:22:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/entra-id-access-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Been working on Identity Governance, access review, and I&amp;rsquo;ll admit it can get confusing real fast!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re still using excel spreadsheet to keep track who should have access or be a member of a security group, then access review is worth looking into!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need a P2 license to play with Identity governance. I still have access to my dev tenant, better put it to use as long as I can&amp;hellip; :wink:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pester Validation Deployments</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/pester-validation-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:24:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/pester-validation-deployments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously, I had a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/bicep-testing-framework/&#34;&gt;bicep testing framework&lt;/a&gt;. The assertions done are more to validate parameter,variables and resource names. You can&amp;rsquo;t assert resource size, or properties, as they depend on runtime deployment. I think pester will be a great fit for this :wink:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pester.dev/&#34;&gt;Pester&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; test framework for PowerShell! When I first got introduced to pester it was for unit testing. As someone who identifies with OPS, it didn&amp;rsquo;t resonate with me, until I saw Kevin Marquette use pester to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pshirwin.wordpress.com/2015/11/06/pester-script-to-test-dns-configuration/&#34;&gt;validate&lt;/a&gt; outcome of what a script was suppose to do. That changed my life!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Testing Framework</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/bicep-testing-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 07:07:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/bicep-testing-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bicep is my goto IaC tools for deploying Azure Resources! I recently had a discussion with my team about validating deployments. Now validation is something I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with using Pester :wink:. I remembered reading about bicep having an experimental feature for testing. I though I&amp;rsquo;d give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just a quick heads up it still is in preview aka not ready for production :grin:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-validate&#34;&gt;Why validate?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some times, you just want to be sure of the current state of a configuration. Is property value really set as I expect? Now you can look it up manually (I&amp;rsquo;d advice against that) or you could use code&amp;hellip; Pester has saved me many of times&amp;hellip; Let&amp;rsquo;s see if bicep can do the same&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Graph Support</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/bicep-graph-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 05:11:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/bicep-graph-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bicep support for Microsoft Graph was a long anticipated feature! Supporting Microsoft Graph in bicep allows you to define the tenant infrastructure (think EntraId among other things) you want to deploy. Currently a subset is support (As of 24th May 2024).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/bicep-graph-support/current-graph-resources.drawio.png&#34; alt=&#34;Graph resources&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those new to &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-gb/azure/azure-resource-manager/bicep/overview?tabs=bicep&#34;&gt;bicep&lt;/a&gt;, bicep is a domain-specific language (DSL) that uses declarative syntax to deploy resources&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just a quick heads up it still is in preview aka not ready for production :grin:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pim Access Review</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/pim-access-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 08:57:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/pim-access-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My team recently got an automation request concerning privileged role access review. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been on the consumer side, so getting some PIM hands-on automation sound like fun!&#xA;This was an interesting challenge on a few levels, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain as we go along&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-pim&#34;&gt;What is PIM?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/entra/id-governance/privileged-identity-management/pim-configure&#34;&gt;PIM (Priveleged Identity Management)&lt;/a&gt; enables you to manage, control, and monitor access to important resources in your organization. The part we&amp;rsquo;ll be focusing on is EntraId Role management. There&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit you can do with PIM! I highly recommend reading the documentation!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with shared queries in Azure Resource Graph (ARG)</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/sharedqueries-arg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 08:17:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/sharedqueries-arg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Azure Resource Graph! When I started with arg in the portal I noticed I coud save my query as private or shared. At that time I didn&amp;rsquo;t think much of until I wanted a better way to manage my queries. That was my &lt;em&gt;aha&lt;/em&gt; moment :grin:. Shared queries makes for a better management experience of your queries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-azure-resource-graph-shared-queries&#34;&gt;What are Azure Resource Graph shared queries?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/resource-graph/tutorials/create-share-query&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; explains it best:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure OpenAI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/azure-openai-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/azure-openai-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;openai-is-the-next-shiny-thing&#34;&gt;OpenAI is the next shiny thing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been following OpenAI developement closely ever since its inception. I was a bit hesitant on upgrading, fearing I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t use its full potential (Also I&amp;rsquo;m quite frugal&amp;hellip;:smirk:). Fortunately there&amp;rsquo;s also a pay-as-you-go plan for using the API directly. This gives you more control on your credits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Microsoft announced their version, I was excited about it, as I&amp;rsquo;m always in Azure. I also have a monthly credit to spend. You do need to &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/oaiapply&#34;&gt;apply&lt;/a&gt; for it, but that process is quite easy. Once you gain access the fun can begin!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Resource Graph (ARG)</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/introduction-to-arg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/introduction-to-arg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Azure Resource Graph (ARG) is one of those things I stumbled upon while learning (or attempting) kusto query. At first, it was just curiousity, and then I realized the possibilities it opens up. In hindsight, it has always been there, but to truly appreciate ARG you need that &lt;em&gt;aha&lt;/em&gt; moment that you&amp;rsquo;ll only get by trying it out! So let&amp;rsquo;s dive into some things I learned along the way&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-azure-resource-graph-arg&#34;&gt;What is Azure Resource Graph (ARG)?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Resource Graph is a powerful tool that allows you to explore, analyze, and manage your Azure resources at scale, efficiently. You can use it to query your Azure inventory, monitor your resource changes, and optimize your resource costs. With the increasing complexity of &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cloud-adoption-framework/&#34;&gt;cloud environments&lt;/a&gt; there is a need for a unified query mechanism. ARG makes that possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new era</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/a-new-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 20:08:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/a-new-era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, glad you can join me on my digital transformation journey. I’ve been in IT some 30+ years now, give or take. My specialty (I use that term loosely) is Microsoft infrastructure. In 2016, I saw the writing on wall at the PSConfEu 2016 conference. There Jeffery Snover talked about &amp;ldquo;digital transformation&amp;rdquo;. At that point I was looking to get started with cloud. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a Microsoft afficionado, so Azure had my preference. I was so convinced of this, I left my employer of 23 years to start my journey. Up to this point my &lt;a href=&#34;https://pshirwin.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;passion&lt;/a&gt; was and still is PowerShell. Cloud is so much more than just scripting. Thing are evolving at a such a rapid rate, sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep up!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
