<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My digital journey</title>
    <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My digital journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:24:38 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://irwins.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pester Validation Deployments</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/pester-validation-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:24:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/pester-validation-deployments/</guid>
      <description>Previously, I had a look at the bicep testing framework. The assertions done are more to validate parameter,variables and resource names. You can&amp;rsquo;t assert resource size, or properties, as they depend on runtime deployment. I think pester will be a great fit for this &amp;#x1f609;&#xA;Pester is the test framework for PowerShell! When I first got introduced to pester it was for unit testing. As someone who identifies with OPS, it didn&amp;rsquo;t resonate with me, until I saw Kevin Marquette use pester to validate outcome of what a script was suppose to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Testing Framework</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/bicep-testing-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 07:07:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/bicep-testing-framework/</guid>
      <description>Bicep is my goto IaC tools for deploying Azure Resources! I recently had a discussion with my team about validating deployments. Now validation is something I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with using Pester &amp;#x1f609;. I remembered reading about bicep having an experimental feature for testing. I though I&amp;rsquo;d give it a try.&#xA;Just a quick heads up it still is in preview aka not ready for production &amp;#x1f601;&#xA;Why validate? Some times, you just want to be sure of the current state of a configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Graph Support</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/bicep-graph-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 05:11:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/bicep-graph-support/</guid>
      <description>Bicep support for Microsoft Graph was a long anticipated feature! Supporting Microsoft Graph in bicep allows you to define the tenant infrastructure (think EntraId among other things) you want to deploy. Currently a subset is support (As of 24th May 2024).&#xA;For those new to bicep, bicep is a domain-specific language (DSL) that uses declarative syntax to deploy resources&#xA;Just a quick heads up it still is in preview aka not ready for production &amp;#x1f601;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pim Access Review</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/pim-access-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 08:57:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/pim-access-review/</guid>
      <description>My team recently got an automation request concerning privileged role access review. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been on the consumer side, so getting some PIM hands-on automation sound like fun! This was an interesting challenge on a few levels, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain as we go along&amp;hellip;&#xA;What is PIM? PIM (Priveleged Identity Management) enables you to manage, control, and monitor access to important resources in your organization. The part we&amp;rsquo;ll be focusing on is EntraId Role management.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with shared queries in Azure Resource Graph (ARG)</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/sharedqueries-arg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 08:17:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/sharedqueries-arg/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Azure Resource Graph! When I started with arg in the portal I noticed I coud save my query as private or shared. At that time I didn&amp;rsquo;t think much of until I wanted a better way to manage my queries. That was my aha moment &amp;#x1f601;. Shared queries makes for a better management experience of your queries.&#xA;What are Azure Resource Graph shared queries? Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s documentation explains it best:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure OpenAI Assistant</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/azure-openai-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/azure-openai-assistant/</guid>
      <description>OpenAI is the next shiny thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been following OpenAI developement closely ever since its inception. I was a bit hesitant on upgrading, fearing I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t use its full potential (Also I&amp;rsquo;m quite frugal&amp;hellip;&amp;#x1f60f;). Fortunately there&amp;rsquo;s also a pay-as-you-go plan for using the API directly. This gives you more control on your credits.&#xA;When Microsoft announced their version, I was excited about it, as I&amp;rsquo;m always in Azure. I also have a monthly credit to spend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Resource Graph (ARG)</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/introduction-to-arg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/introduction-to-arg/</guid>
      <description>Azure Resource Graph (ARG) is one of those things I stumbled upon while learning (or attempting) kusto query. At first, it was just curiousity, and then I realized the possibilities it opens up. In hindsight, it has always been there, but to truly appreciate ARG you need that aha moment that you&amp;rsquo;ll only get by trying it out! So let&amp;rsquo;s dive into some things I learned along the way&amp;hellip;&#xA;What is Azure Resource Graph (ARG)?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new era</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/a-new-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 20:08:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/posts/a-new-era/</guid>
      <description>Hi, glad you can join me on my digital transformation journey. I’ve been in IT some 30+ years now, give or take. My specialty (I use that term loosely) is Microsoft infrastructure. In 2016, I saw the writing on wall at the PSConfEu 2016 conference. There Jeffery Snover talked about &amp;ldquo;digital transformation&amp;rdquo;. At that point I was looking to get started with cloud. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a Microsoft afficionado, so Azure had my preference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://irwins.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://irwins.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Irwin. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in IT some 25+ years. I&amp;rsquo;m passionte about automation!&#xA;I am familiar with a number of programming languages, but am strongest in PowerShell.&#xA;Feel free to keep in touch using your preferred social media – I have linked to all of my frequently-used accounts in the bottom left! Please keep in mind that all opinions expressed on this website and social media are my own, personal views; they are not reflective of, nor endorsed by, my employer.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
