<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My digital journey</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My digital journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 08:17:21 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with shared queries in Azure Resource Graph (ARG)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/sharedqueries-arg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 08:17:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/sharedqueries-arg/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Azure Resource Graph! When I started with arg in the portal I noticed I coud save my query as private or shared. At that time I didn&amp;rsquo;t think much of until I wanted a better way to manage my queries. That was my aha moment &amp;#x1f601;. Shared queries makes for a better management experience of your queries.&#xA;What are Azure Resource Graph shared queries? Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s documentation explains it best:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure OpenAI Assistant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/azure-openai-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/azure-openai-assistant/</guid>
      <description>OpenAI is the next shiny thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been following OpenAI developement closely ever since its inception. I was a bit hesitant on upgrading, fearing I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t use its full potential (Also I&amp;rsquo;m quite frugal&amp;hellip;&amp;#x1f60f;). Fortunately there&amp;rsquo;s also a pay-as-you-go plan for using the API directly. This gives you more control on your credits.&#xA;When Microsoft announced their version, I was excited about it, as I&amp;rsquo;m always in Azure. I also have a monthly credit to spend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Resource Graph (ARG)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/introduction-to-arg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/introduction-to-arg/</guid>
      <description>Azure Resource Graph (ARG) is one of those things I stumbled upon while learning (or attempting) kusto query. At first, it was just curiousity, and then I realized the possibilities it opens up. In hindsight, it has always been there, but to truly appreciate ARG you need that aha moment that you&amp;rsquo;ll only get by trying it out! So let&amp;rsquo;s dive into some things I learned along the way&amp;hellip;&#xA;What is Azure Resource Graph (ARG)?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new era</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/a-new-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 20:08:03 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/a-new-era/</guid>
      <description>Hi, glad you can join me on my digital transformation journey. I’ve been in IT some 30+ years now, give or take. My specialty (I use that term loosely) is Microsoft infrastructure. In 2016, I saw the writing on wall at the PSConfEu 2016 conference. There Jeffery Snover talked about &amp;ldquo;digital transformation&amp;rdquo;. At that point I was looking to get started with cloud. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a Microsoft afficionado, so Azure had my preference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Irwin. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in IT some 25+ years. I&amp;rsquo;m passionte about automation!&#xA;I am familiar with a number of programming languages, but am strongest in PowerShell.&#xA;Feel free to keep in touch using your preferred social media – I have linked to all of my frequently-used accounts in the bottom left! Please keep in mind that all opinions expressed on this website and social media are my own, personal views; they are not reflective of, nor endorsed by, my employer.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
